# Franca Uvere

Address: Lagos, Nigeria 100242 Phone: +2349020949301

### Email LinkedIn GitHub

## Professional Summary

I am a professional software engineer and full-stack developer, specializing in backend web development and software architecture design and implementation. I have extensive experience with technologies such as Flask, Python, MySQL, and WordPress, and excel at creating efficient web applications. I have a proven track record of leading development teams, integrating complex databases, and delivering customized solutions for various clients.

Experience

### **Automation Engineer**

Freelance Developer | March 2024 – Aug 2024

- Utilised automation techniques for data gathering and compilation for the purpose of model training.
- Utilised automation techniques to improve workforce coordination and monitoring using third-party automation tools/services.
- Utilised Backend technologies and automation tools to automate workflow processes, thereby, increasing efficiency by 30%.

## **Woo-Commerce Developer**

Freelance Developer | Jan 2024 - Aug 2024

- Collaborated with a UI/UX engineer to build an E-commerce website.
- Employed woo-commerce for commercial and management efficiency for client.
- Built a fully customised website using Wordpress, and ensuring optimal user experience and streamlined business operation.

### **API Integration and Database Management**

Freelance Developer | Jan 2024

- Collaborated with Ethos Solution Inc for database management operations.
- Contributed to improving system performance and data integrity through secure and clean API integration.

## Webhook Engineer | ClickUp Public API

Freelance Developer | December 2024 – January 2024

- Designed, Implemented, and Integrated webhooks using the POSTMAN API for the ClickUp Public API.
- Ensured seamless integration, allowing for automated workflows and improved data collection.

## **Python Programming Tutor**

Independent Contractor | Dec 2023- Jan 2024

- Provided personalized Python programming tutoring sessions to post-graduate individuals.
- Developed customised learning plans tailored to the needs and proficiency.

#### **NLP Development for Next Word Predictor**

Freelance NLP Developer | October 2023-November 2023

- Lead a team of four machine learning engineers in data collection and analysis for development of a natural language prediction application.
- Implemented a Next Word Predictor application using Natural Language Processing(NLP) techniques.
- Integrated the trained model with the application for user friendly use.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Various Back-End Technologies and Frameworks: Python and Node JS
- Front-End Technologies: HTML, CSS, React-JS, Tailwind-CSS, JavaScript.
- Database design and management (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Mongo-DB, etc)
- API infrastructure design, implementation and integration
- Automation using Selenium, Scrapy and third-party services such as JIRA, etc.
- Quality Assurance, Unit and Integration Testing using Python and JavaScript tools.
- Version Control with Git/Github.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Certification in Software Engineering**

ALX-Software Engineering Training Programme (Sponsored by MasterCard and ALU-Holberton School)

- Completed professional development in the 12 Month Software Engineering training programme.
- Awarded Certificate of Completion

## **Bachelor of Engineering: Chemical Engineering**

2021 Jan – Current

- First class (4.67 / 5.0), University of Lagos, Nigeria.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Online Banking Platform**

A financial Application

- Role: Lead Developer
- Team: Managed a team of 4 software engineers
- Key Reponsibilities:
  - Designed and Implemented a prototype web application for online banking.
  - Integrated a MySQL database for secure and efficient data storage
  - Ensured application had all essential features of an online banking platform including account management, transactions and security protocols